Back with the market right here on
ETNow. Let me just revisit what the
market has settled in at because
we started off quite okay. Half a
percent higher is where we're currently
at. 115 points up in the green. It's
really about some of the technology and
metal names today even though the index
has eased off just that tad bit. The
health of the broader market is quite
buoyant. Key Fin Tech higher by 3%,
Coforge up higher 3%, Nalco, Hindustan
Zinc and Vedanta are also holding up
quite smartly. But let me now welcome on
board Gopal Balachandran, uh the CFO at
ICICI Lombard joining in on the show
right now to talk about how their
performance has been. Gopal, great to
have you on ETNow. Your combined ratio
has improved yearly and sequentially.
What were the key drivers behind this
improvement in the ratio and how much of
this improvement is structural versus
cyclical and can you sustain this going
forward?
From an ICICI Lombard standpoint, I
think the philosophy with which we have
been writing our businesses has always
been to drive
uh growth profitably as it makes sure
that we are able to kind of
write businesses from a top-line
standpoint which we think is viable.
And at the same time make sure that you
are able to give give an outcome whether
it is in the form of combined ratios or
more importantly
the return on equity that we exhibit to
shareholders is something that we want
to see on a sustained basis. Exactly to
your point.
And that is what something that we have
been able to do through over the last
several years.
To your point on uh while specifically
answer the current combined ratios point
that we spoke, but just to kind of speak
it in the context of how we have been
able to deliver it sustainably.
Uh this is something that we have also
called out in our
analyst
transcript last evening as in to say
that if you look at the last 10 years
the last 10 years what we have been able
to deliver is a combined ratio of
roughly at about 100 on an average of
about 102.9%.
Now this if you look at vis-a-vis the
industry
the industry combined for the last years
has averaged about 115%. So, one of the
points that we have always spoken about
is to try and see
if and continue to maintain the delta
visibly the industry combined by more
than 10 basis points.
It's something that we have always been
able to kind of do as an institution
from an ICICI Lombard standpoint. So,
that's one.
The second on the ROE point that I spoke
again if you look at the last 10-year
average
uh our ROE the last 10 years would have
kind of delivered roughly about 19% uh
returns.
Industry
uh average for the last 10 years and ROE
has been about 4%.
So, again there again we have had a huge
outperformance and that is also
reflective of now coming back to the
specific
question that you asked for this
particular year as well
uh the whole thought process is to try
and see how we can kind of keep
improving our combined.
Right. Uh you know, the other thing I
wanted to talk about is the investment
income which has come in below
estimates. Was this driven by market
volatility, asset allocation, or any
one-offs? And should we expect a equity
recovery in Q1 of FY27?
I think for us uh while while I
responded earlier in the context of
insurance operations which is reflective
in the combined numbers
I think for us equally what we are very
very happy about from an ICICI Lombard
standpoint is the fact that
we have been able to consistently
deliver returns on the investment book.
Again, I will kind of keep it uh to
let's say long-term averages.
Uh again the same 10-year horizon is
what I would speak about. On a 10-year
basis again if you look at the average
uh realized return that we have been
able to deliver as an organization has
been roughly at about 8.7% or there
about.
So, there again I think what we have
been able to consistently deliver is
returns uh of managing the overall
investment book quite efficiently.
And that's what is reflected in the
long-term averages.
Uh coming back to the specific uh for
the period under consideration, I think
obviously quarter four has exhibited a
bit of volatility and for us, we do
invest both in debt securities as well
as equities as an asset class. And we
have seen how what markets had had
experienced, particularly in quarter
four. And which is why
in so far as our investment income is
concerned, while we would not have been
able to realize as much of capital gains
as what one would have normally expected
given the market volatility. But what we
are very very excited with is the fact
that if you look at the realized return
that we have been able to get even for
the current year gone by, our realized
return actually has kind of gone up on
any on an year-on-year basis. So hence,
I think we are very happy with the way
how the investment assets has played
out.
Right. And what about the retail health
because that has been very strong. What
are the key drivers behind this
momentum? Additionally, how is pricing
evolving in this segment and how is it
that you see any or rather whether do
you see any risks from rising
competition or a higher base impacting
growth and market share?
I think
amongst the segments what ICICI Lombard
has spoken about as areas of preferred
uh,
business lines that we would want to
kind of stay invested in. Retail is
definitely kind of features
among those list.
Um, just to kind of again refresh and
put this in context, we have been
speaking
to all of you on the importance of our
investments that we want to do on
coming up with good product ideas, at
the same time make sure that we are able
to kind of distribute it quite
efficiently. And that's what we have
been kind of largely investing in both
on new product launches that we have
done pretty much in the last
12 to 18 months and obviously continued
expansion and distribution. What this
has led to is exactly the point that you
said. As in we have been able to
outperform the industry by almost about
2x.
Uh
and I am very very happy with the way
how things have played out. Even our
market share is reflective of that. I
think it used to be about 3.3% 1 year
back. Currently we are at about 4.1%.
Uh so very happy with the way how things
have played out. The good part for us is
it's not just about
gaining market share, but more
importantly I think the quality of the
book that we have been able to
underwrite is also reflective of
the loss ratio outcomes. I think it even
in the past quarters we did speak about
on retail health the loss ratio range
that we are comfortable writing is
between 65 to 70% and if you look at the
full year numbers for FY26
on the retail health indemnity book, our
loss ratios finally ended at ended
roughly at about 64%.
So hence very happy with the way in
terms of how
it's been a it's been a it's been a
growth that was aided by
great positive top line contribution and
the same time more importantly also
contributing to the bottom line as well.
And
hi Mr. Balachandran, is Harsh also
joining in?
How do you see pricing trends across
motor health commercial lines,
especially on motor and health because
you've seen competition and therefore
you've been calibrating your growth.
Give us a sense of how pricing intensity
is playing out.
If you look at the industry combined
ratios for motor,
it's roughly at about
128%.
This number 1 year back used to be about
124%.
So in that sense obviously the market
participants went
a lot more aggressive in driving price
aggression and that obviously resulted
for the industry combined ratios to get
significantly deteriorated
at 128%.
However, for ICICI Lombard, I think we
have always tried to kind of as I said
grow businesses profitably. In fact, our
combined ratios on motor have actually
kind of come down.
So, hence very very happy with the way
how
we have been able to drive the change.
And this is also reflective of
how things have come back
for ICICI Lombard. If you look at for
example, the first half of the year in
motor we actually lost market share.
Uh exactly to the point of where the
market went too much of competitive
intensity.
But second half, I think we have been
able to kind of see a significant
rebound. Obviously, also aided by a lot
of governmental  regulatory
reforms.
But ICICI Lombard has been able to kind
of gain incremental market growth.
That's how we will continue to play in
the way how we want to drive uh
big business line way forward.
Coming to your point on commercial lines
uh
that's been a segment for ICICI Lombard
which has been
at its strength.
At an aggregate level, we would have had
a market share of almost anywhere
between
13 to 14%. This cuts across
fire, engineering, marine, cargo,
liability, etc. etc.
But having said that, in the last 12
months in specific
uh fire has been very very competitive
on price.
So, hence obviously we have been a bit
guarded.
Right. And lastly, what are the key
growth drivers you think for for '27
across segments? And which segment, more
importantly, will be the biggest
profitable segment for you?
Honestly in the current challenging
times
it'll be too difficult for us to really
kind of say that what kind of market
growth can one expect and therefore
what should ICICI Lombard be doing?
But having said that, uh
I think what we have always spoken to
all of you is that uh
from an ICICI Lombard standpoint, what
we want to kind of largely get measured
at is uh
try and keep improving market share
against, and that is exactly what we
have uh tried to deliver even if you
look at uh the second half and more
importantly the quarter four gone by.
And that is something that we will look
forward to even when we head into FY27.
As if to say that
vis-à-vis the industry, we would want to
continue to see at an aggregate level.
This cuts across all lines of
businesses. We would want to see ICICI
Lombard gaining market share anywhere
between 100 to 200 basis points over the
industry growth numbers.
Uh so that's what we would kind of work
with, and at the same time and more
importantly try and keep delivering a
sustained return on equity to our
shareholders, uh which could range
anywhere between I would say 18 to 20%.
Uh the those are the two key matrices
that we would work with, uh try and
create an alpha over industry growth
numbers, and uh sustainably deliver
return on equity to shareholders.
Thank you so much. Uh uh we we leave it
at that. Uh that's that gives you that
gives us a very good perspective with
regard to Lombard's numbers and what to
expect going forward. Uh but what we'll
do is leave it on a very short break. On
the other side, we'll quickly start to
understand what the trends with regard
to the F&O space look like and what are
they really indicating with regard to
our markets. Stay with us.